Lesson 53. In the public interest, the Scandinavian countries are much admired all over the world
第53课。为了公共利益，斯堪的纳维亚国家在世界各地都倍受钦佩
evolve: v.   逐渐形成
for their enlightened social policies. Sweden has evolved an excellent system for protecting
为了他们开明的社会政策。瑞典发展了一个绝佳的保护系统
high-handed: adj. 高压的，专横的, incompetent: adj. 不够格的，不称职的
the individual citizen from high-handed or incompetent public officers. The system has worked so well
来自高管或无能的公职人员的公民。该系统运行良好
that it has been adopted in other countries too. The Swedes were the first to recognize that
它也已在其他国家采用。瑞典人是第一个认识到的人
public official like civil servants. Police officers, health inspectors or tax collectors can
公务员像公务员。警察，卫生检查员或收税员可以
make mistakes or act over zealously in the belief that they are serving the public. As long
犯错误或热心行事，因为他们相信他们正在为公众服务。只要很长
safeguard: v.   保护
ago as 1809, the Swedish parliament introduced a scheme to safeguard the interest of the individual.
瑞典议会以前是1809年，提出了一项保护个人利益的计划。
parliamentary: adj. 国会的
A parliamentary committee representing all political parties appoints a person who is suitably
代表所有政党的议会委员会任命一个适当的人
grievance: n.   不平，冤屈
qualified to investigate private grievances against the state. The official title of the person
有资格调查针对国家的私人不满。该人的正式头衔
is, Justity Ombudsman. But the Swedes commonly refer to him as the J.O. or, Ombudsman.
是，公正监察员。但是瑞典人通常称他为J.O.或者，监察员。
The Ombudsman is not subject to political pressure. He investigates complaints large and small
监察员不承受政治压力。他调查了大小的投诉
that come to him from all levels of society. As complaints must be made in writing,
从社会各个层面来到他身边。由于必须以书面形式提出投诉
the Ombudsman receives an average of 1,200 letters a year. He has eight lawyer assistants to
监察员平均每年收到1200封信。他有八名律师助理
secretive: adj. 保密的
help him and examines every single letter in detail. There is nothing secretive about the Ombudsman's
帮助他并详细检查每个字母。申诉专员没有什么秘密的
correspondence: n.   来往信件
work for his correspondence is open to public. Inspection, if a citizen's complaint is justified,
他的信件工作向公众开放。检查，如果公民的投诉是合理的，
the Ombudsman will act on his behalf. The action he takes varies according to the nature of the
监察员将代表他采取行动。他采取的行动会根据
alter: v.   改变
complaint. He may gently reprimand an official or even suggest to parliament that allow the altered.
抱怨。他可能会轻轻谴责官员，甚至建议允许改变的议会。
The following case is a typical example of the Ombudsman's work. A foreigner living in a Swedish
以下情况是申诉专员作品的典型例子。居住在瑞典的外国人
village wrote to the Ombudsman complaining that he had been ill-treated by the police. Simply because
村庄写信给申诉专员，抱怨说他已经受到警察的虐待。仅仅是因为
he was a foreigner, the Ombudsman immediately wrote to the chief of police in the district asking
他是外国人，申诉专员立即写信给该地区的警察局长
him to send a record. Of the case, there was nothing in the record to show that the foreigner's
他发送记录。在案件中，记录中没有什么可以证明外国人的
accusation: n.   谴责，指控
complaint was justified in the chief. Of police strongly denied the accusation. It was impossible
酋长的投诉是有道理的。警察强烈否认了这一指控。这是不可能的
for the Ombudsman to take action, but when he received a similar complaint from another foreigner
申诉专员采取行动，但是当他收到另一个外国人的类似投诉时
in the same village. He immediately sent one of his layers to investigate the matter. The lawyer
在同一个村庄。他立即派出他的一层调查此事。律师
ascertain: v.   查出，查明
ascertained that a policeman had indeed dealt roughly with foreigners on several occasions.
确定一名警察确实多次与外国人进行了大致处理。
prejudiced: adj. 有偏见的，不公平的
The fact that the policeman was prejudiced against foreigners could not be recorded in the official
警察对外国人有偏见的事实无法记录在官员中
files. It was only possible for the Ombudsman to find this out by sending one of his representatives to
文件。申诉专员只有将他的一位代表发送给
check the facts. The policeman in question was severely reprimanded and was informed that if any
检查事实。有问题的警察受到了严厉谴责，并被告知，如果有的话
prompt: adj. 即时的
further complaints were lodged against him, he would prosecute it. The Ombudsman's prompt action
进一步提出了针对他的投诉，他会起诉。监察员的及时行动
that once put an end to an unpleasant practice which might have gone unnoticed.
这曾经结束了可能没有引起注意的令人不愉快的练习。